<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on HirschDaniel</title>
    <link>https://hirschdaniel.com/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on HirschDaniel</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.133.1</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 07 Sep 2024 10:26:37 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://hirschdaniel.com/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Vim Ctags Cheat Sheet</title>
      <link>https://hirschdaniel.com/posts/vim-cheat-sheet/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Sep 2024 10:26:37 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hirschdaniel.com/posts/vim-cheat-sheet/</guid>
      <description>There are dozens of good vim cheat sheets online. Why do another one? This one is a cheat sheet tailored to my workflow for generating ctags. Let&amp;rsquo;s have a look.
Generate ctags like this (replace js with whatever language files you want to ignore, if any. I don&amp;rsquo;t code javascript, but my projects contain tons of js files, so I exclude them):
ctags -R -f ~/.ctags --exclude=&#39;*.js&#39; &amp;lt;path-to-project&amp;gt;
If your project contains a language that is not supported by ctags, but is related to another familiar language, you can use langmap.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hugo Cheat Sheet</title>
      <link>https://hirschdaniel.com/posts/second/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Sep 2024 10:19:39 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hirschdaniel.com/posts/second/</guid>
      <description>Here&amp;rsquo;s a list of useful hugo commands I regularly use.
# Build your hugo project hugo # Create a new content file hugo new &amp;lt;path&amp;gt; # For example: hugo new posts/hugo-cheat-sheet.md # Run the hugo development server hugo server Remember to set draft = false for content to be displayed.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>I decided Wordpress is for freaks and dumped it</title>
      <link>https://hirschdaniel.com/posts/first/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 10:48:07 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hirschdaniel.com/posts/first/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been publishing wordpress websites for well over 10 years now. Wordpress was working well for me once I was familiar and knew a set of plugins to use. I knew exactly which caching, security, image compression, host, etc. to install to get things running smoothly. Somehow, this still doesn&amp;rsquo;t feel simple enough. No way every website is built like this.
Back in school, I learned that a website is just HTML (for content) and CSS (for styling).</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
